democracyinaction.org 2006-06-15

# Democracy In Action: Technology for the Masses: Affordable Online Campaign Tools and Services

|  |   
---|---  
 |   
 |   
 |   
 |   
 |   
 |   
 |   
  
First Name   
  
Last Name   
  
Email   

### Introduction

DemocracyInAction.org respects each individual’s right to personal privacy. We will not share your information with any third-party organization without your explicit permission to do so. Personal information you provide is stored in a secure location and is accessible only by designated staff. We will collect and use information through our Web site only in the ways disclosed in this statement.   

### Information Collection and Usage

DemocracyInAction.org collects two types of information about users: optional and/or voluntary information that users provide; and information that is automatically recorded in a standard, web server log file each time a page request is made. 

Part of the nature of DemocracyInAction.org relates directly to congressional constituencies and the ability of representatives to hear and to communicate with members of their districts or states. To this end, we collect names and mailing addresses from users who choose to post directly on action pages we provide for senators, representatives, and other officials. We may use this information in aggregate the same way we use all aggregate information we collect. 

DemocracyInAction.org offers a bi-weekly electronic newsletter to users. We gather the e-mail addresses of users who voluntarily subscribe through links on various pages of the sites. If users choose to opt-in to our email list (or the email list of a Participating Organization), we may use this information to alert users to new services or features we believe will be of interest to those them or to send action alerts or other pertinent information. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we always present the option to not receive these types of communications. 

DemocracyInAction.org Participating Organizations have all agreed to adhere to our strict privacy policy and will not share any personally identifiable information gathered on those pages with a third party without the express consent of its users. 

We will NOT collect personally identifying information which our users divulge about other people, such as the information provided in our tell-a-friend feature. 

DemocracyInAction.org does not actively market to children, and we never knowingly ask a child under 13 to divulge personal information. 

We may collect demographic data through automatic logging files in order to enhance the usefulness of our site. 

### Cookies

A "cookie" is a small file assigning you a unique ID that is placed on your computer by a web server. DemocracyInAction’s web site uses cookies within our action centers in order to identify the action taker and make it easier to take action. We may also from time to time use cookies on the homepage so that frequent visitors are not presented a pop-up window each time they visit 

### My Causes

For the My Causes section of the web site, the information collected will be used to create profiles based on your interests and geographical location in order to link you to the appropriate legislators. These user profiles will only be used to improve the user interface, and will not be shared. 

### Linking 

We offer links to other Web sites. Please note: When you click on links to other Web sites, we encourage you to read their privacy policies. Their standards may differ from ours. 

Our Web site will offer forums and message boards. Please be advised that information posted in these venues becomes public knowledge. 

### Access to Information 

Users may access their own personal information and contact us about inaccuracies they may find. Users may delete their information from our database by going to the My Causes section and editing their personal profile. Registered subscribers can remove their names from our subscriber list, and the lists of our organizations through the My Causes section as well. 

### Problem Resolution 

If problems arise, users may contact DemocracyInAction.org by emailing us at info@democracyinaction.org. We are committed to resolving disputes within 72 hours. 

### Data Storage and Security

The data we gather from users is stored on our servers along with everything else on our servers, and the same security measures protect users' data as protect our own internal data. We use industry-standard methods to protect the confidentiality and integrity of your personal information. Please note, however, that while there is no such thing as "perfect security" anywhere on the Net, we protect your data just as we protect our own. Furthermore, access to personal data is restricted within the company, and that all employees are aware that personal data is private. 

If you have any further questions about privacy or security, please contact us by sending an email to: info@democracyinaction.org. 

### Your Choice to Opt-Out

DemocracyInAction.org provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us at the point where we request information about you. If you do not wish to receive such communications, please select one of the options below.   

  * You can submit a comment through our Feedback form 
  * You can send email to info@democracyinaction.org 
  * You can log in to My Causes and remove yourself from the organizations you do not wish to be contacted by. 

DemocracyInAction.org reserves its right to modify this privacy policy at any time
